<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bestia - Developer Documentation on Bestia Game</title>
    <link>https://docs.bestia-game.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bestia - Developer Documentation on Bestia Game</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="https://docs.bestia-game.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Attacks</title>
      <link>https://docs.bestia-game.net/docs/mechanics/skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.bestia-game.net/docs/mechanics/skills/</guid>
      <description>Attacks The magic and the usage of it plays a crucial role in the Bestia universe. The users should be able to be deeply involved into magic spell creation and research.
 The words Attacks and Spells are equally used.
 The system must allow the user to describe or discover newly innovative ways to combine spells. Yet the research should be fun and entertaining. Bestias can learn attacks by two means:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>https://docs.bestia-game.net/docs/mechanics/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.bestia-game.net/docs/mechanics/resources/</guid>
      <description>Resources Resources are raw materials used to sell to other players. They can be used to craft items or construct buildings. Resources can be obtained by the following means:
 Killing enemies and loot them Gathering of natural resources in the game world Using special extracting buildings or devices Recycling of existing items   The item loot from monster should be logically correct: a dead wolve would very likly not drop iron ore or golden coins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://docs.bestia-game.net/docs/client/entities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.bestia-game.net/docs/client/entities/</guid>
      <description>Entities The Bestia server entities are synched to the client also represented there also under the name Entities. An entity is described by a set of components which is attached to it and by a certain kind of logic synched between the client and the server. Not every component is synched though. This can depend on various factors for example party membership (ConditionComponent is only synched between members of the same party), or ownership or view distance (mostly only entities in view distance are synched).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://docs.bestia-game.net/docs/mechanics/dev-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.bestia-game.net/docs/mechanics/dev-resources/</guid>
      <description>Artwork and Design The general art style will be comic like as for example World of Warcraft. This helps the game to get fast assets as its easier then archiving foto-realism and also these styles are more timeless.
UI Design Currently no final UI Design was found. Feel free to contribute!
Logos Currently no final Bestia Logo was found. Feel free to contribute!
Fonts Currently the font usage is not finally decided.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://docs.bestia-game.net/docs/mechanics/general/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.bestia-game.net/docs/mechanics/general/</guid>
      <description>General Mechanics Main Story The main story revolves around the player whose world was destroyed due to a so-called rift event. The magic pushed into his world and merged it with another one. This altered the physical properties of both worlds and mostly destroyed them. He is thrown into a new one and must learn to survive on his own (while exploring the new world, making friends and foes.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://docs.bestia-game.net/docs/mechanics/statusvalues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.bestia-game.net/docs/mechanics/statusvalues/</guid>
      <description>Status Values Status Values are the base values from which the basics for all ingame calculations are performed. There are four main types of values: Base Values, Status Valus, Condition Values and Effort Values. The Status Based Values (SBV) play a special role.
The sophisticated status system describes the current state of an bestia (or simply any living entity) and does not strictly apply only to biological entities. The status system is important to calculate all battle related effects in the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://docs.bestia-game.net/docs/server/datatypes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.bestia-game.net/docs/server/datatypes/</guid>
      <description>Datatypes All locations and entities are represented via fixed point numbers to avoid incorrectness with floating points over a bigger distance (see The perils of floating point).
Positioning The basic datastructures for positioning and collisions are found in net.bestia.model.geometry. Most notable the Vector3 datatype.
It uses long as datatypes for the coordinates and thus has a range between -9.223.372.036.854.775.808 to 9.223.372.036.854.775.807 which means if we can represent at the best a position resolution of 1mm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Artificial Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://docs.bestia-game.net/docs/server/ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.bestia-game.net/docs/server/ai/</guid>
      <description>Artificial Intelligence The AI system in Bestia will set new standards. Bestias and NPCs alike should be able to create long-term plans, so-called game plans or GPs for short. They then follow this strategy until observations or influences from the game world force them to abandon this plan or the plan is fulfilled.
Bestias look for ways to get the highest possible inner happiness. They must sleep, eat and feel attracted to mana currents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Battlesystem</title>
      <link>https://docs.bestia-game.net/docs/server/battlesystem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.bestia-game.net/docs/server/battlesystem/</guid>
      <description>Battle system The battle or attack is performed in various stages. Equipments or Status effects either alter the DamageVars or expose certain hooks which are called during the damage calculation. In the case of the DamageVars this object is
The attack itself either provides a script to completely manage the effect which takes place during cast or it provides certain callbacks for damage calculation stages which are getting called while applying the damage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bestia</title>
      <link>https://docs.bestia-game.net/docs/mechanics/bestia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.bestia-game.net/docs/mechanics/bestia/</guid>
      <description>Bestia In areas with high mana concentration, so-called mini rift events are formed. At these neuralgic points, Bestia are materialized and enter the respective worlds.
Catching TODO
Breeding Bestias can be interbred in order to improve certain statistics. The player can pair certain individuals of Bestia in order to produce offspring. In order to breed a Bestia the following criteria must be met:
 A male and female is required Bestias of the same kind (humanoid, formless etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bestia Master</title>
      <link>https://docs.bestia-game.net/docs/mechanics/master/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.bestia-game.net/docs/mechanics/master/</guid>
      <description>Bestia Master The intro game tells players how to become a Bestia Master. They came into direct contact with an ephemeral mana crystal that changed their nature through magic and connected them to the mana flows. They are therefore receptive to the influence of mana and are able to communicate with the beings that emerge from this mythical energy: the Bestias.
The attachment to mana also explains why Bestia masters were able to survive the destruction of their world relatively unscathed and to pass on to the next world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Environment</title>
      <link>https://docs.bestia-game.net/docs/mechanics/environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.bestia-game.net/docs/mechanics/environment/</guid>
      <description>Environment Bestia uses a sophisticated temperature and environment system to drive weather simulation and the effects on the players environment.
These simulations should be based on certain basic values which are determined location-dependent, but can be changed by interaction with the players. Also natural changes through the world (seasons) should lead to an adjustment of these values. Due to the changes of the environmental values tiles have to be adapted to the world itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Items</title>
      <link>https://docs.bestia-game.net/docs/mechanics/items/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.bestia-game.net/docs/mechanics/items/</guid>
      <description>Items Items can be optained by the player and carried around. The amount of items limited to each entity is determined via its Inventory. Each Bestia (and also a lot of other entities), have their own inventory with different sizes.
Items are mostly crafted by the players. Its quite rare to obtain direct item drops from killed enemies. Instead its very common to loot resources when enemies are killed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Server Scripts</title>
      <link>https://docs.bestia-game.net/docs/server/scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.bestia-game.net/docs/server/scripts/</guid>
      <description>Scripte Das Skript-System in Bestia wird genutzt um flexible Programmausführung für verschiedenste Zwecke zu ermöglichen. Dazu gehören vor allem die Effekte von benutzten Items, Attacken, das Verhalten von Gespawnten Entities usw.
Als Skriptsprache wird auf JavaScript gesetzt, da diese sowieso im HTML Client verwendet werden muss und so eine weitere Sprache für das Spiel gespart werden kann. Aktuell wird die Nashorn Javascript Engine von Java 8 benutzt. Sollte sich dies als Performance Engpass herausstellen so kann später mit mittlerem Aufwand auf die V8 Engine von Google umgerüstet werden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stories and Quests Generation</title>
      <link>https://docs.bestia-game.net/docs/server/quests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.bestia-game.net/docs/server/quests/</guid>
      <description>Literature https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/2016/09/02/how-to-procedurally-generate-culture/ http://www.gdcvault.com/play/1024143/Procedural-Narrative http://pcg.wikidot.com/pcg-algorithm:procedural-puzzles-and-plot-generation http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/abstract/document/5740836/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Generation</title>
      <link>https://docs.bestia-game.net/docs/server/world-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.bestia-game.net/docs/server/world-generation/</guid>
      <description>World Generation Bestia uses a specialized library called worldgen for world creation. It is a clusterable generator which is cabable of dividing the world creation workload onto multiple, different machines. With this framework it should be possible to create million of square kilometers without hitting any memory limit on the servers.
Algorithmus  Grundparameter Erstellung von Influencemaps Wasserspiegel festlegung Erzeuge die Wasser Maske Erzeuge von Gewässern und Flüsse Temperaturkorrektur Biom Zuordnung vornehmen Terrain Features verteilen und erzeugen Biom Optimierung Tilemap Erzeugung Biom Features Erzeugung der Städtekandidaten Erzeugung und Verteilung von Bodenschätzen  Grundparameter The following base parameters are used to generate the map:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>